<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>AshLogs</title>
    <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on AshLogs</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://voidash.github.io/blog/avatar.png</url>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/avatar.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2025 AshLogs. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:30:25 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://voidash.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #8</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 10:30:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/8/</guid>
      <description>Once men turned their thinking over to machines in the hope that this would set them free. But that only permitted other men with machines to enslave them.
   The world in which we live now is perfect summary of dynamics of modern western world. The rise of technofeudalism, purchasing power parity difference in military spending, people worrying about economic stagnation when almost everyone is rich and these xenophobic people reluctantly wanting immigrants to do their dishes while voting against immigration highlights the hypocrisy of western society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #7</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 May 2025 00:20:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/7/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;There are no shortcuts in programming problem solving&amp;rdquo;. Looking at the post The Best Programmers I know, I am reminded of my worst mental model when it comes to programming problems. I believe that &amp;ldquo;If the task is simple enough then it is not necessary to touch the fundamentals of the tool i am using for finding solution, hoping somebody else has already encountered it and there will be solutions around the internet&amp;rdquo;, This surprisingly works for lots of tasks but there are cases where   I misjudge the problem and it turns out to be gory mess which requires significantly more effort</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #6</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2025 02:49:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/6/</guid>
      <description>Hanlon&amp;rsquo;s razer says, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t attribute to malice, which can be explained by Stupidity&amp;rdquo;. A junior programmer introducing RCE to codebase might be oblivious to it. A politician might genuinely be working for the interest of people, but may not know the nuances of potentially pernicious policies they are lobbying for. Michael Saylor gives a little bit of history regarding Washington&amp;rsquo;s death. . George was subjected to multiple rounds bloodletting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #5</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 02:49:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/5/</guid>
      <description>Modern dictionaries have lost their vividness, unlike Webster&amp;rsquo;s 1913, which embraces the richness of language. Growth happens in cycles, and even Newton needed normal conditions to refine his discoveries, reminding us that dormancy isn&amp;rsquo;t failure. Also little bit on structure of rap music to Rust&amp;rsquo;s out-of-thin-air values, fuzz testing, and AI-driven development tools. It&amp;rsquo;s my week worth of Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity
Inspired by Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity by Thorsten Ball, I spend about 30 minutes daily exploring curious and joyful topics, shared weekly as &amp;ldquo;Interesting things that happened last week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #4</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 23:56:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/4/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity by Thorsten Ball, I spend about 30 minutes daily exploring curious and joyful topics, shared weekly as &amp;ldquo;Interesting things that happened last week.&amp;rdquo;
Why and Who is the Audience? Primarily for personal reflection, this writing aims to shape how AIs perceive and remember my cognitive aesthetics, potentially reaching a wider audience in the future.
This week&amp;rsquo;s notes dives into philosophy (Kant, consciousness), LLMs (training, RLHF pitfalls, visualization), some product ideas (LoksewaGPT, repo loader), and miscellaneous tech insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #3</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 23:48:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/3/</guid>
      <description>Parse, don&amp;rsquo;t validate is interesting read. &amp;ldquo;Parsing is conversion of unstructured data to slightly structured data&amp;rdquo; . If every computation follows input -&amp;gt; process -&amp;gt; Output model, then parsing is quintessential. Complex systems are not completely linear when you reason the expected initial behavior.,But we can always break it down to reasonable chunks. The state change between various chunks might require its state input to be in exact format where validation kicks in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy &amp; Curiosity #2</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 23:48:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/2/</guid>
      <description>I had some deep heated discussion regarding essence of time, deep work, garnering interests with Belove dai. This left a deep impact on me and has basically caused me to rethink my goals. The deepest insight was hidden behind the philosophy of palmer luckey, who built Oculus and currently founder of Anduril industries. It&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;The Reverse Engineering Effect&amp;rdquo; . Define end goals with clarity to identify the exact steps or actions required to achieve the goal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy and Curiosity #1</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 19:05:31 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/2025/1/</guid>
      <description>Hey, Welcome to #1 edition of Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity.
What is it? Inspired from Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity by Thorsten Ball. Each day, I take at least 30 mins or less writing about the things that either stems from curiosity or things that brings me Joy. At the start of the week, i will share it as &amp;ldquo;Interesting things that happened last week.&amp;rdquo;
Why and Who is the Audience Again Taking it from tweet shared on this week&amp;rsquo;s Joy &amp;amp; Curiosity</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Postgres on Digital Ocean Droplet</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/postgres-on-digital-ocean-droplet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 15:44:27 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/postgres-on-digital-ocean-droplet/</guid>
      <description>Step-by-step guide to install and configure PostgreSQL on a Digital Ocean Ubuntu droplet, including user setup, remote access configuration, and network settings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Casio Calculator</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/hacking-casio-calculator/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 15:15:25 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/hacking-casio-calculator/</guid>
      <description>Deep dive into hacking the Casio fx-991es calculator by exploiting buffer overflow vulnerabilities in its nX-u8 chip architecture. Learn about Harvard architecture, memory manipulation, and ROP techniques.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pragmatic way to create a Rust based Web application | From Start to Deployment</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/rust-webapp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 22:22:33 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/rust-webapp/</guid>
      <description>Complete tutorial on building and deploying a Rust web application using Actix-web and Tera templating engine. Covers project setup, templating, systemd service configuration, and Nginx deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Approaching Rest API Design</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/rest-api-design-handbook-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 20:49:32 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/rest-api-design-handbook-summary/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive guide to RESTful API design principles covering Richardson Maturity Model, CRUD operations, URI design patterns, resource archetypes, HTTP methods, and best practices for scalable web APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tor Is Beautiful</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/tor-is-beautiful/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 20:49:32 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/tor-is-beautiful/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Tor network architecture and its role in internet privacy. Learn how onion routing, relay circuits, and layered encryption protect anonymity while enabling freedom of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pokhara Memories</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/mustang-memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:25:45 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/mustang-memories/</guid>
      <description>A poetic memoir of travels through Pokhara and Mustang, Nepal. Reflections on cycling, boating at Fewatal, roller skating, and the profound experiences that shape our journey through life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Nushell</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/introducing-nushell/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 20:07:44 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/introducing-nushell/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Nushell, a modern cross-platform shell written in Rust that treats everything as structured data. Compare traditional Bash workflows with Nushell&amp;#39;s intuitive table-based approach.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uninstall System Apps in Android With ADB</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/uninstall-system-apps-in-android-with-adb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:39:07 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/uninstall-system-apps-in-android-with-adb/</guid>
      <description>Remove bloatware and system apps from Android devices using ADB (Android Debug Bridge). Step-by-step guide to uninstall unwanted manufacturer apps at user level without root access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to switch between Nepali and English keyboard layouts in Linux</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/switching-keyboard-layouts-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 10:52:37 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/switching-keyboard-layouts-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>Configure romanized Nepali keyboard layout in Linux using setxkbmap. Works across GNOME, KDE, XFCE desktop environments on X11. Quick setup guide for switching between English and Nepali input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scripting with Rust: A basic Guide</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-as-script/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:29:05 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-as-script/</guid>
      <description>Learn how to use Rust for scripting tasks. Covers primitive Rust scripts with rustc, cargo-script for dependency management, and practical examples of file operations and testing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rust New Competitor to C and C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c&#43;&#43;/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:20:48 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c&#43;&#43;/</guid>
      <description>Why Rust is becoming a viable alternative to C and C&#43;&#43; for systems programming. Explore memory safety, thread safety, modern tooling, and Rust&amp;#39;s advantages in embedded systems and WebAssembly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Install Rust And The Linker It Requires On Linux</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</guid>
      <description>Quick guide to installing Rust on Linux including the required linker setup. Covers installation steps for both Arch-based and Debian-based distributions using rustup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and Linux</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</guid>
      <description>This post discusses how to setup time on linux if you are affected by dual boot or by discharged CMOS battery. It starts with a fix for a dual boot system and on latter part there is a fix for cmos battery problem.
Dual Boot Messing Up Time Universal Time or UTC is primary time standard by which the world regulates clock and time. GMT is timezone and UTC is time standard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflecting Myself: 2020</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/2020/post-class-reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/2020/post-class-reflection/</guid>
      <description>this blogpost is part of the assigment given to us on course ENGT 102. Just posting because it reminds me of my shortcomings.
 Handling the situation: The train is out of the track; Deviated from its journey. Looks like its heading the opposite path. How can i bring it back? I should assess the situation, understand the condition, and make plans according to it but Somehow my brain manages to abstract things out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Types of Operating systems on basis of processing</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2019/operating-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2019/operating-systems/</guid>
      <description>Explore different types of operating systems based on process handling: batch, time-slice, multithreading, embedded, and real-time systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AC Vs  DC : which is more dangerous?</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</guid>
      <description>AC vs DC comparison: discover why alternating current is more dangerous than direct current. Learn voltage differences and health impacts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alias Linux Command Explained succintly</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/alias-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/alias-linux/</guid>
      <description>Create custom Linux command shortcuts with alias. Learn to substitute strings for commands and boost your terminal productivity efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> Understanding inheritance in java : SuperclassVariable can reference a Subclass Variable</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</guid>
      <description>Understand Java inheritance: how superclass variables reference subclass objects. Learn polymorphism with practical parent-child class examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linux Chmod command explained</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/chmod/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/chmod/</guid>
      <description>Complete chmod tutorial: change file permissions in Linux using symbolic and octal notation. Master user, group, and other access controls.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Multithreading in java(Java programming guide)</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</guid>
      <description>Master Java multithreading: create threads using Runnable interface and Thread class. Learn thread-based concurrency with practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Generics in Java</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understand-generics-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understand-generics-java/</guid>
      <description>Master Java generics with practical examples. Learn parameterized types, type safety, and how to write reusable code without casting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorithms : A brief example</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/what-is-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/what-is-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to algorithms: step-by-step processes for solving problems. Learn key characteristics like definiteness, finiteness, and feasibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Law of Stoichiometry</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/law-stoichiometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/law-stoichiometry/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive guide to the five laws of stoichiometry: conservation of mass, definite proportions, multiple proportions, and gaseous volumes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>9&#39;s complement Method: Computers use those?</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2017/computers-subtract/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2017/computers-subtract/</guid>
      <description>Learn how computers use 9&amp;#39;s complement method for subtraction using the same circuit as addition. A practical guide to computer arithmetic.</description>
    </item>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Joy and Curiosity</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/joy-and-curiosity/</guid>
      <description>archives</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random</title>
      <link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/</guid>
      <description>archives</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
