<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>AshLogs</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on AshLogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:25:45 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://voidash.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Pokhara Memories</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/mustang-memories/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:25:45 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2023/mustang-memories/</guid><description>Memories: Tour to Mustang A written memoir of the trip from my side.
{{ image-resize Memories%20Tour%20to%20Mustang%203e183a1db1924e789780c63ce0ed2a7c/nice_profile.png &amp;ldquo;100x100&amp;rdquo;}}
You are a child of universe
No less than the trees and the stars
you have the right to be here
And whether or not it is clear to you
no doubt the universe is unfolding as it should
Cycling in pokhara: all the eons before me and the time my life conjured the back and forth between nihilism and fatalism</description></item><item><title>Introducing Nushell</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/introducing-nushell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jan 2022 20:07:44 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/introducing-nushell/</guid><description>At it&amp;rsquo;s core Shells are just interactive user interface that exposes OS tools and services. This blog is a introduction to Nushell , a cross-platform shell written in Rust . We already have had fair share of shells like Bash, Zsh, Fish etc. Why do we need yet another shell? All existing shells have one thing in common, They all treat as if everything is a text. Enter Nushell where Everything is a structured data.</description></item><item><title>Uninstall System Apps in Android With ADB</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/uninstall-system-apps-in-android-with-adb/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 10:39:07 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/uninstall-system-apps-in-android-with-adb/</guid><description>Computer is required
Android is modified by manufacturers where they add some applications and games that can&amp;rsquo;t be uninstalled through application manager. Some of them are straight for promotion and advertisement; I guess that makes the phone a little bit affordable. But wheb users don&amp;rsquo;t have option to remove the bloatware, is simply unacceptable. Well through ADB(Android Debug Bridge), those bloatwares can be uninstalled for a user level.
First enable Developer settings in your phone.</description></item><item><title>How to switch between Nepali and English keyboard layouts in Linux</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/switching-keyboard-layouts-in-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 10:52:37 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2022/switching-keyboard-layouts-in-linux/</guid><description>Romanized Nepali has become de-facto standard for typing Nepali. This is going to be a short guide on how to enable romanized nepali on Linux. Keep in mind that there is nothing to download as linux comes with the keyboard layout by default. However some of the linux distribution like Ubuntu make this process even simpler by giving a GUI interface. So This post will link external posts for those distribution and will only contain barebones method to change layout, which will work for any desktop environment running on X11 Server.</description></item><item><title>Scripting with Rust: A basic Guide</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-as-script/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 14:29:05 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-as-script/</guid><description>Was Rust built to be a scripting language? the types which you can use for crawling web, extracting links, sending mails etc. Generally stuff that serve single functionality with limited scope. Python fits into that domain perfectly and it is pleasant to write scripts in python. But what about Rust? The language doesn&amp;rsquo;t even come with a garbage collector, and you might as well fight its borrow checker until it deems your code is memory safe.</description></item><item><title>Rust New Competitor to C and C++</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c++/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:20:48 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c++/</guid><description>This post tries to reason why Rust might be choice for new projects instead of C and C++. This is a bold statement and there is a need to discuss the types of projects where a comparision is being made. i.e Systems Programming. Going back a bit further, and taking a look at the motivation for these languages shines a beam of light about the main goal of these languages.</description></item><item><title>How To Install Rust And The Linker It Requires On Linux</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</guid><description>This post discusses how to install rust on linux. Well installation process is pretty simple but sometimes minimal distribution like Arch maynot bundle the linker and rustup (a tool used to install and manage rust installation) also doesn&amp;rsquo;t include linker
Build Essential contains Linker Rust doesn&amp;rsquo;t include linker (which is required for generating execuatable ) on its installer. To install the linker, first check the type of distro you have</description></item><item><title>Time and Linux</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</guid><description>This post discusses how to setup time on linux if you are affected by dual boot or by discharged CMOS battery. It starts with a fix for a dual boot system and on latter part there is a fix for cmos battery problem.
Dual Boot Messing Up Time Universal Time or UTC is primary time standard by which the world regulates clock and time. GMT is timezone and UTC is time standard.</description></item><item><title>Reflecting Myself: 2020</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/2020/post-class-reflection/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/2020/post-class-reflection/</guid><description>this blogpost is part of the assigment given to us on course ENGT 102. Just posting because it reminds me of my shortcomings.
Handling the situation: The train is out of the track; Deviated from its journey. Looks like its heading the opposite path. How can i bring it back? I should assess the situation, understand the condition, and make plans according to it but Somehow my brain manages to abstract things out.</description></item><item><title>Types of Operating systems on basis of processing</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2019/operating-systems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2019/operating-systems/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Operating system is system software that manages the resources of computer, one that directly talks to your hardware. When your computer boots up , operating system is loaded into your main memory and and it starts performing tasks. These tasks are processes for your computer and depending upon the task you may have one or many processes for a single task. To have a better understanding, if you are on Windows , Take a look at Task manager and you will find a Running processes tab.</description></item><item><title>AC Vs DC : which is more dangerous?</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com If You are looking for quick answer then AC is dangerous. So what makes Alternating current more dangerous than Direct Current? I guess we should take a look at their own respective features. Features of Direct Current
Direct Current Direct Current Voltage – Time Graph
If DC source is rated for X Volts then maximum voltage that DC source can provide is X. if your Source is rated for 12 V then max Voltage it can provide is 12 V.</description></item><item><title>Alias Linux Command Explained succintly</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/alias-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/alias-linux/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Purpose to substitute a String in place of commands used in linux. Note: commands can include paramaters too.
If you are familar with CMD then you would certainly know cls clears the screen. but in linux shell there is command called clear to wipe out terminal junk. so if i want to use cls in linux or unix like OS terminals then i would use $ alias cls='clear'</description></item><item><title> Understanding inheritance in java : SuperclassVariable can reference a Subclass Variable</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Superclass : A parent class Subclass : A child class that inherits Superclass
class A{ //superclass or parent class //some generic code } class B extends A{ //subclass or child class of A //some generic code } it may seem esoteric at first, but its true that superclass variable can reference a subclass object .This aspect is quite useful when superclass object needs parameters same as subclass object which is not part of that superclass object.</description></item><item><title>Linux Chmod command explained</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/chmod/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/chmod/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
CHMOD aka Change mode is the command present in linux or unix like systems. Purpose
To change the mode of a file for specified user classes according to specified permissions with different function.
Making it simpler it is used to change the permission of file . The basic syntax looks like
chmod options permissions filename Permissions Permissions are boundary for file access that can be defined for each user classes.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Multithreading in java(Java programming guide)</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Process Based Vs Thread Based
In your operating system , you are able to run many processes at a single time i.e you can scroll through your facebook messages in Google Chrome while watching new Avengers movie in VLC media player. This concept is process based thread model and Multi Threaded operating system can perform such tasks.If you want to learn more about operating system on the basis of processing , you can visit here.</description></item><item><title>What are Generics in Java</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understand-generics-java/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understand-generics-java/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Lets start why generics is needed rather than identifying what generics really are. Through the use of generics one can create classes,interfaces and methods and specify what kind of data it is working upon. Lets start up with example : Many algorithms logic is same no matter what kind of data they are working upon. Stack algorithm logic is same no matter which type of data you are working with ,i.</description></item><item><title>Algorithms : A brief example</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/what-is-algorithm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/what-is-algorithm/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Algorithm is step by step finite and systematic process which defines how particular problem can be solved to derive a desirable solution. How to make a tea? There is specific process to make a tea, and that’s algorithm. How to capture photos in old reel camera? First you need to open camera .Second you may set exposure, aperture length according your requirement and then you may click the button.</description></item><item><title>Law of Stoichiometry</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/law-stoichiometry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/law-stoichiometry/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
There are five laws of stoichiometry which are basis for understanding fundamental concepts of chemistry. Those five laws are:
Law of conservation of mass Law of constant or definite proportions Law of multiple proportions Law of equivalent or reciprocal proportions Law of gaseous volume Law of conservation of mass It states that total mass of reactant is equal to total mass of product or simply put any substance that undergoes chemical reaction will have same mass throughout the reaction.</description></item><item><title>9's complement Method: Computers use those?</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2017/computers-subtract/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2017/computers-subtract/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
computers are intricate to understand at the superficial level, but at its core all you will see are logic. Logic makes everything. The invention of transistors allowed us to create logic gates and those logic gates allow computers to add. couple of XOR gates and AND gates can create a full adder. but how do computers subtract? they use something called 1’s complement because computer developers thought “screw this , we are not going to build another circuit for subtraction, rather we will use same circuit board that we use for addition”.</description></item><item><title>Random</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/random/</guid><description>archives</description></item></channel></rss>