<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>AshLogs</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content on AshLogs</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:20:48 +0545</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://voidash.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Rust New Competitor to C and C++</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c++/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 17:20:48 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/rust-new-competitor-to-c-and-c++/</guid><description>This post tries to reason why Rust might be choice for new projects instead of C and C++. This is a bold statement and there is a need to discuss the types of projects where a comparision is being made. i.e Systems Programming. Going back a bit further, and taking a look at the motivation for these languages shines a beam of light about the main goal of these languages.</description></item><item><title>How To Install Rust And The Linker It Requires On Linux</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/install-rust-linux/</guid><description>This post discusses how to install rust on linux. Well installation process is pretty simple but sometimes minimal distribution like Arch maynot bundle the linker and rustup (a tool used to install and manage rust installation) also doesn&amp;rsquo;t include linker
Build Essential contains Linker Rust doesn&amp;rsquo;t include linker (which is required for generating execuatable ) on its installer. To install the linker, first check the type of distro you have</description></item><item><title>Time and Linux</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 08:23:51 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2021/linux-and-time/</guid><description>This post discusses how to setup time on linux if you are affected by dual boot or by discharged CMOS battery. It starts with a fix for a dual boot system and on latter part there is a fix for cmos battery problem.
Dual Boot Messing Up Time Universal Time or UTC is primary time standard by which the world regulates clock and time. GMT is timezone and UTC is time standard.</description></item><item><title>Ac Vs Dc : which is more dangerous?</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/ac-dc/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com If You are looking for quick answer then AC is dangerous. So what makes Alternating current more dangerous than Direct Current? I guess we should take a look at their own respective features. Features of Direct Current
Direct Current Direct Current Voltage – Time Graph
If DC source is rated for X Volts then maximum voltage that DC source can provide is X. if your Source is rated for 12 V then max Voltage it can provide is 12 V.</description></item><item><title> Understanding inheritance in java : SuperclassVariable can reference a Subclass Variable</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0545</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/understading-inheritance-java/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Superclass : A parent class Subclass : A child class that inherits Superclass
class A{ //superclass or parent class //some generic code } class B extends A{ //subclass or child class of A //some generic code } it may seem esoteric at first, but its true that superclass variable can reference a subclass object .This aspect is quite useful when superclass object needs parameters same as subclass object which is not part of that superclass object.</description></item><item><title>The Art of Multithreading in java(Java programming guide)</title><link>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://voidash.github.io/blog/posts/2018/multithreading-java/</guid><description>Migrated from logicaletter.com
Process Based Vs Thread Based
In your operating system , you are able to run many processes at a single time i.e you can scroll through your facebook messages in Google Chrome while watching new Avengers movie in VLC media player. This concept is process based thread model and Multi Threaded operating system can perform such tasks.If you want to learn more about operating system on the basis of processing , you can visit here.</description></item></channel></rss>